let me take a look at the code really
quickly here you say off the Pod
research and then you know we're going
to do it yeah we're gonna look right now
[Music]
all right we're rolling okay
cool that was a an interesting way to
start yeah my phone I'm trying to record
on my phone today
um because I'm I'm not at home and uh
like my phone was overheating and then
it got like it went on vibrate mode but
then it just didn't stop vibrating so
it's just a constant
it kind of sounded like a razor yeah
yeah it was crazy like right as we
started your phone just immediately like
I could hear it just like just vibrating
who knows it may explode during this
episode and then I'll switch to my other
uh webcam but yeah I figured I'd give it
a shot
awesome awesome dude how's it going you
adjusted back to normal life from the
live hacking event scene
uh not really though you know I I've
been I've been pretty rich I was not
feeling yeah still in the Fallout not
feeling uh super great yet I think my
sleep is still like adjusting and uh it
was weird because when I was traveling I
don't know if this happens to you but
I'm sleeping like
three maybe four hours a night seriously
oh my gosh for like two weeks no wait
and I was functioning like totally I
would die like I I would totally die
even like looking back I was like in the
moment I was like I have no idea how I
slept four hours last night because I
don't feel like it and I was just like
going through a whole day like not
sleeping until like three a.m and then
I'd wake up at like 7 30 and like be
fine and then I got home and I've been
sleeping more than I usually do like
seven and a half hours and I feel like
terrible I'm like trying to like figure
out what I have no idea how you do that
because I I mean I did that maybe one
night maybe I got like a six and I was
still doing fine the next day and I was
like all right you know circadian
rhythms hacked
um but no if I get less than six I'm I'm
done for him a dude for sure
yeah I mean that's normally how I am
like anything less than six and I'm I'm
doomed even like I mean anything more
than six doesn't really seem to help me
either
um I generally like have pretty bad
sleep so even if I sleep like eight and
a half hours in a night or something
which never happens for me but I
probably just still feel the same wow so
it kind of just takes like a couple
hours for me to like fully wake up and
then um I'm like good to go I definitely
need it's like a slow I definitely need
more than six though like six is like
I'm skating by and then like seven or
eight is like all right I'm feeling
rested let's go let's go get it so I
don't know yeah I was hoping that
magically when I got home I would like
then be a night person and I would be
able to stay until 3am and sleep four
hours a night and get a bunch more work
done but no no I am immediately back to
like oh it's nine o'clock it's it's time
for bed it's not a sleep study right
yeah yeah and that really didn't like
give me the answers I was hoping for
like I think for everybody it's a little
bit different but when I got my sleep
study done they basically were like yeah
you like you snore a little bit and you
might want to look into that I was like
that's it they're like yeah that's it
sucks good luck I was like like what the
heck like what am I supposed to do with
this so yeah I pick for everybody it's a
little bit different but uh you know
sleep study if you can get your
insurance to cover it definitely I'd
recommend getting one done just like
half the have the analytical data and
like the input from a sleep scientist
about what's going on yeah for sure my
dad had one done and he had uh you know
got a CPAP machine or whatever and it
like totally changed his life so yeah
yeah yeah cool anyways awesome
sleeping into security right
um so yeah so the first link I had in
the new section for today was uh once
again another Banger from the asset note
team and I'll give credit where credit's
due this time this is not shubs even
though it has acid note written on it
this is actually Dylan Pinder which is a
uh who's a security research researcher
at assetnote
um and this is about the share file rce
which is actually a product that I've
used fairly extensively so I was like oh
what the heck is going on here this is
crazy how simple this RC was it's a
beautiful exploit but um you know the
other stuff coming from Acid node a lot
of times has been a lot more challenging
than this one looked
yeah yeah I mean it's always they're
always anytime you see a blog post from
asset node it's always very high quality
and it goes into a ton of detail about
like their thought methodology and the
path that they took to get there and
they do a really good job of explaining
sort of like the attacker mindset as
they're coming towards something that
like from the title you can tell is very
severe um you know it's an rce so I
think that provides sort of a unique
insight and oftentimes it's not like the
super straightforward type of like oh I
put like ID like
you know like it's usually a little bit
more in depth and it goes into like how
they discovered it and yeah the files
that they were looking for and the
patterns and stuff and I think like
that's really useful because a lot of
times you see sort of like the black box
approach where it's like I was just
fuzzing this end point I saw an
interesting parameter I try to command
injection and it worked and that's it
you don't really get the understanding
for like what that looks like on the on
the back end or like the engineering
side or like if you were doing source
code review how that might
um how that might look and so I think uh
it's really awesome to see the blog
posts that they put out because they go
into that level of detail for sure as
always I love the methodology and the
write-up they they talk about they dump
all the files they they talk about
um this this uh I guess function that's
getting called to parse the cookie Set
current principle from session cookie
um which you know if you were just kind
of looking through the code you might
assume that that is going to be
something that does you know an
authentication check and in fact the
title of that section they they titled
authenticated but not really
um because that once you double click
into that that you know that call it
just skips over it if it doesn't find
the cookie that it was looking for
um and so it's like okay well sort of
that was gonna be an authentication
check and there's some other pieces down
the line where
um you know you would assume
Authentication was was um was necessary
but they kind of you know weave around
out of those and eventually end up
finding a past reversal not in
um let me see if I can find the name of
the parameter it's not in the parameter
that you would think
um
here it is right here yeah so it's it's
not in the parameter that allows you to
specify the path it's a it's a in the
upload ID parameter
um and that gets concatenated with the
path a little bit later
and even though the path is actually
um sanitized uh the uh upload ID is not
which meaning which results in the path
reversal which allowed them to get
arbitrary file right so that was a
really I think that was a really good
method and then this one also sort of
has a little bit of an A A Twist to it
which is you need to have a a valid
parent ID within the application and so
that parent ID
um you might assume would be something
you might have to have like a valid
folder or a valid um you know ID of a
folder or something but really they
found that all you have to do is have a
um string that does not fail when it
gets AES decrypted and so it doesn't
matter what that string is it's not used
anywhere but if it if it is if it gets
uh you know if it passes the AES
decryption then you're able to to do the
attack so they they outline really well
um how AES Works how
um the pkcs seven padding works and how
they were able to use that to really
reliably guess a value for this
um parent ID I think it was only 128 or
256 tries that it took to brute force
and then they find a valid value that
will pop and result in them getting a
shell so once again
you know big round of applause to the
acidity they killed it
yeah yeah I think it's um it's really
interesting because this is something
that we talk about in appsec a lot where
it's like validation versus verification
and
like tote like a textbook example is JWT
tokens where they're just checking is
this a valid JWT token not is the
contents inside of the JWT token valid
and so those are two very different
things like if you're just checking that
this is a valid JWT token it could
decode properly and that's it and you're
not actually checking who signed it or
is the key correct and is the person who
they're saying they are in the JWT token
actually who they are who they are like
if you're not doing those checks
then that's where these little like
weird edge cases because you might read
through this and I'm sure it's like
whoever wrote this like didn't think
that this was going to be an issue they
probably were like yeah just you know
check if this is valid and go forward
and
that's not enough you need to like also
just verify like do that extra step and
that that Pitfall I think hits in a lot
of different areas uh yeah and you know
this is just another example of you know
in a big product as well like just that
classic kind of case where they detected
but they didn't fully verify yeah I
don't know about on the JWT front I kind
of feel like that's the whole cell
of the GWT though is that like you know
it should be sort of self-authenticating
because it's signed by the you know by
the person that that has the private key
right so you know and obviously that
doesn't always work out to be the case
but
um you know these different Technologies
do have their different pitfalls and
that is you know in in the JWT scenario
as you mentioned that if somebody does
you know find a way to forge a token or
get their hands on the private key or
whatever then you're just totally
screwed so yeah yeah so much of that
comes down to like which Library you're
using too like if you're just using a
library that separates out like
validation and verification then that
might just like put you in a big Pitfall
where you're using the built-in library
or something but it has an extra
function that you needed to call and you
didn't know it or something like that
and that oftentimes is just either a
documentation problem or something even
stupider than that and you know it it
happens to everybody so I think it's
just uh you know it's cool to see it in
the wild and I think it's just something
that you should always keep keep an eye
out for and just like you know check and
see are they are they actually verifying
by my JWT contents can I just give it
any sign JWT and will it work so
um I guess bringing it back to the blog
post I did have one more thing that I'll
just try to explain from you know
without you having to go and read the
blog post which is like I I've done a
couple deep Dives on AES and um and you
know the padding portion of it for
padding Oracle attacks so for those of
you that have done that in the past and
want a little bit of a refresher the way
that the uh PK cs7 padding works is that
you've got your you know you've got your
16 uh bite blocks and then when you
don't have when your data does not sum
up to 16 bytes the rest of that 16 bytes
is filled by the value that is the
number of remaining bytes so if you've
got 15 uh you know bytes in that in that
block and you need to get one more that
last byte is going to contain the a byte
that points to one and if it's you know
14 then
yeah zero zero two zero two right
um and so that that's something that I
had back there you know in in the memory
database and that but just doesn't come
you know sometimes when I need it to so
there's your little refresher on on um
AES uh padding protocol for any of you
that are interested in that that low
level of cryptography yeah yeah yeah you
should probably see this a lot in CTS
too like if you decrypt an AES block and
it's not exactly the block length then
it'll always have like trailing bytes
that usually are not printable because
it's from like 0x01 to 0x0f and so
oftentimes you'll be like oh what is
that oh right I need to unpad it and
there's like a
some copy paste function that I always
use off a stack Overflow to do that in
Python yeah yeah no python man this is
just another great example because the
exploit here is written in Python is
like you really if you're gonna try to
get to this level of you know Pro
hacking you need to be pretty handy with
python or
you know some sort of scripting language
so that you can just write out these
pocs pretty quickly
yeah 100 alrighty so let's see what else
we got on the list for today
um
so uh babook Jane a pretty well known
hacker uh he tweeted out on Twitter uh
when was this a couple days ago
um originally that they had like a full
read srf and a headless Chrome instance
they were trying to escalate it somehow
they were trying a bunch of different
things they could access gcp metadata
but the creds were super restricted so
they couldn't really escalate that they
tried a bunch of different internal and
external subdomains again couldn't
really find anything useful couldn't
really escalate it
ask for some help on Twitter and today
they re they quote tweeted their own
tweet and they said solved and so the
solution was that they figured out that
they could hit the Chrome debugger
instance on Port 9222 uh on slash Json
specifically I believe
um which will dump but I I guess a lot
of data about what's going on I've never
actually used this port so I'm not super
familiar with how it works but he did
link to some docs that describes like
what this what this API is used for and
the type of data that that is provided
there
um and he said that it allowed exfil
trading data from other users who were
hitting the Chrome uh the Headless
Chrome browser instance so it seems that
it basically gives like an overview uh
of all the data and stuff that's
happening within that Chrome browser
instance and uh that's a really awesome
creative way to escalate that I think
that's a default Port would be my guess
the 922 yeah that is a default port and
I I threw this in the news articles for
this week because we've mentioned this
on the Pod before or the um the debug
instance there and it's great to see
someone actually pop something with it
and that's
um you know when you hit that slash Json
endpoint um on the on the dev tools
protocol
it dumps a list of all of the uh
available sort of websocket targets that
you can connect to for the devtools
protocol
um and some of that stuff will leak
information about any other tabs that
are open in the browser right so if you
have other people using that headless
Chrome instance then that could
absolutely leak information about you
know what what what page they're looking
at or what user information would be in
there so that's that's something that I
hadn't I was I thought about that route
a little bit more for like accessing
sort of chrome internals and being able
to Pivot around a little bit from there
but I actually didn't think about it
just from like the raw you know data
being leaked via that slash Json
endpoint about other users so it's got
sort of an application Level uh you know
use as well when exporting headless
Chrome instances
yeah super interesting and I think like
it's also like a kind of unique thing
where we've talked about headless
browsers specifically as well but
um like it's it's a unique attack
scenario where it's not it's like more
than an srf because you're in the
Headless browser specifically and so
this is the type of functionality that
only exists in like certain scenarios
but I think it's a good thing to put in
your word list and and to check for for
sure yeah let me go see if I can find
the episode where we talk about that
it's I want to say it was one of the
earlier on episodes where
um yeah it was episode nine headless
browser ssrf so we talked about that
that was a fun episode because those are
such cool that's it's such a cool blood
class
yeah yeah and live overflow replied to
his his follow-up tweet and linked a
video that live over posted
um uh just almost two years ago now
august 19 2021 uh that talks about
hacking a screenshot service so live
overflow made uh a screenshot like a
headless browser screenshotting
challenge for the cyber security uh
challenge Germany in 2021 and then made
a follow-up video about like how it
worked how to exploit it a bunch of
different uh information about how you
could go about escalating it and all
that kind of stuff and
um
replied to that tweet and was like oh
yeah this is exactly what I did so so uh
I think it's really cool you know this
shows if you you know fall live overflow
if you follow the content creators who
are making awesome awesome content in
the cyber security space
a lot of the time that will help you
later down the road even if it's a video
from two years ago yeah for sure man I
I've just started recently to appreciate
I think fully how awesome life overflow
is they do a lot of really awesome
content and really good methodology
stuff too so I think I think uh you know
I think as as a hacker that sort of I
don't know I feel like at this point I'm
a little bit more focused on
um you know doing the hacking and doing
the research and stuff like that rather
than
um you know consuming content on cyber
security
um but I think I'm missing out a good
bit because there's a ton of awesome
content creators that have kind of
sprung up since I started bug Bounty
that I've kind of missed out on I kind
of missed the the start of their you
know uprise and uh I think I gotta go
back and kind of do a little you know
indexing of how awesome those people
might be
yeah for sure I mean there's so many
people who are creating amazing stuff um
recently I can't remember their names
but there's like one or two people who
I've noticed a lot uh in oh by the way
your camera's completely Frozen yeah I
think I think it just died I think it's
done
dude yeah oh no all right okay well I'll
just keep I'll keep talking or should
you want me to pause go ahead you're
good you're good continue
okay cool yeah so um no I just think
that there's a lot of really uh really
interesting awesome new Talent that's
popped up into the hacking space not
even specifically within bug Bounty but
um just sort of like across the board
um and I think a good example is there's
a couple hackers who I've noticed
recently and I wish I could think of
their names off the top of my head or
find them quickly
but they've been posting a lot of like
Hardware security type stuff one of them
has been doing a lot of mobile hacking
where he's been taking especially these
iot devices like smart plugs or smart
cameras and stuff and looking at how the
mobile app is collecting that data where
is it sending to
uh you know what other data might it be
collecting alongside of that with
location data and that sort of stuff and
another one of them has been doing
similarly a lot of like Hardware stuff
but more on the hardware teardown side
where they've been taking popular
Hardware devices or like I love that
stuff dude um Alibaba type Alternatives
and tearing those apart and seeing like
how does this work on the inside is this
vulnerable and you know X Y or zua
um and I think you know just putting
that data out there and having it
somewhere that's readable in this case
generally it's Twitter threads
um it makes for an awesome addition to
the security like learning community
where now you have additional resources
that you can pull on and you can look at
real world examples of how this type of
stuff works yeah for sure man yeah I I
love the you know we kind of talked
about this before but like teardowns and
stuff like that man those things are so
helpful whenever you're trying to like
you know figure out how a device is
working I know I really heavily relied
on some of those for some of the live
hacking events we've done and you just
go online and you find someone who has
like you know broken it out and like
linked all the uh you know FCC like
pages and stuff like that and I'm just
like oh gosh I love you
yeah exactly yeah it's uh I mean I think
oh I did find one of them
um hacks Rob he's the one who's been
doing a lot of the like software side
with mobile apps and figuring out how
um how the how the app is collecting
data and where it's sending to and all
that kind of stuff
h-a-x-r-o-m okay into Twitter hacks Rob
uh and then I wish I could find the
other guy I know it starts with an A
uh we'll link it we'll link it down
below but yeah um you know any any info
info that you can put out there just I'd
recommend trying to put it out there I
personally am not the best at this
honestly it's hard I'm more of like a I
see a cool tweet and I retweet it
instead of creating my own unique
content but
um I think you know I love to see that
stuff uh out in the space and and
hopefully I can do a little bit more of
it myself I did find the other the other
person it's atc1441 uh I believe they
also have a YouTube channel which I
think is how I originally found them I
was just like on YouTube and out of
nowhere this like Hardware like tear
down hacking video like popped up on my
feed and I was like wow that's like not
something I see every day and I saw his
video and it was like really cool and
then he showed up on my Twitter feed as
well so yeah atc1441 he's more of like a
hardware uh focused hacker I would say
um his most recent thread was a couple
days ago and he went over this it's a
called a data frog handheld emulator
whoa it's very cheap it's on AliExpress
and it's like you know like a game
handheld like emulator game boy knockoff
type type device you know very cheap
um but you know it was a tear down of
like how it works what the chips are and
that kind of stuff and again like this
type of just it doesn't have to be
vulnerability research so much it's just
like informational knowledge and
research and just sharing that out
publicly is super useful for future
research I think a lot of the time
you'll see
um I I mean this happened multiple times
where I'm tearing apart a hardware
device I see a chip number I Google that
chip number and the second link is a
blog post that's titled reverse
engineering the oh my God it's like I'm
like oh this is perfect this is exactly
what I was looking for so honestly just
putting that info out there is so useful
um and it's it's so great for future
hackers even if it's you know just some
random thing that you're looking at yeah
like we said before even if you don't
get anywhere just like you know having
gone through the process sharing your
knowledge is is super helpful but like
you said as well it's very hard to do
that you know it's not necessarily the
easiest thing in the world to do so
um yeah that that could definitely be
that could definitely be something that
if someone wants to sort of ease into
content creation that could be a great
way to go yeah for sure
um all right so sort of along the lines
of iot devices slash Apple application
you know physical applications
um this next piece that I had in the
note was a tweet by orange which anytime
orange tweets anything uh for those of
you that aren't familiar it's orange
underscore 8361
um orange Psy on Twitter uh you know
this is
if you're the target bad if you're if
you're just a researcher good oh hell
yeah exactly you wake up and you you
roll over and you read that blog post
right away so that's what I did and um
yeah he he wrote up a version of it um
talking about how uh this specific
Google search appliance which is
actually sort of like a on-prem version
of Google Search which I didn't know
existed
um they kind of bought one on eBay and
uh and pulled figured out a way to get
the the firmware
um from like some old Google group like
you know weird Google group that
shouldn't be public right which is just
like the most hackery thing like that is
what you talk about all the freaking
time and it goes in there and he's like
okay you know here's a link to it oh
sweet I can just like iterate through
these numbers and download literally
every single version of the firmware and
what's great is like this is something I
think I've done like I've tried this one
before and it's it's not worked like
yeah it's really awesome that this
worked
um but like basically for sure he was
like looking on on this form thread from
like oh when was this uh 2015 or
something oh my God somebody linked and
they were like hey I was trying to
download this here's like the link but
it's not work talking and so they took
that link and they like went on web
archive and they figured out the valid
like version number ranges and then they
just Brute Force to every potential file
version like with that formatting on the
same post and you know it came back with
actual files which is also kind of crazy
because it this whole this whole product
Google search Appliance looks like it
would be extremely deprecated by this
point but oh yeah I'm sure uh maybe it's
being maintained to some extent or maybe
they still just have like
versions of the files up there or
something but it's really really crazy
that I I mean I had never even heard of
this thing I didn't even know it was a
thing I've never seen a photo of one uh
I didn't know we needed Hardware like
this so uh I think as a hacker if I had
known this would it would have existed I
would have been like oh I want to get my
hands on that yeah if you scroll down to
the very end he has a timeline
um and it says that Google said the
issue is not severe enough to qualify
for a reward
I'm like are you kidding me this is RC
but you know I I think that's probably
because this product is not being used
you know or not being actively used by a
large user base and so the risk is just
not there but yeah the the the bug
itself the bugs the the flow is really
really interesting so definitely worth a
read if you're interested in tearing
apart iot devices and figuring out
exactly how he does it and also I just
kind of love oh actually now that I'm
going through it he's got some of this
stuff censored
yeah no no but some of the stuff is not
censored but if you scroll halfway down
he he starts he starts doing like he
writes in the post like all right this
is the contents of etsy Shadow right
this is like the password to like you
know uh this config you know sort of
thing I'm just like oh my gosh you just
totally wrecked it you know when you're
like writing plain text passwords of
these like embedded devices all over the
Internet
um super badass and also I just wanted
to shout out I really do like the way
that he broke down the various Network
Services that are listening on various
ports the iptables rules that you know
show access to those
um and that sort of thing too that's a
great way to sort of uh take a an attack
surface and you know get it in front of
you feel like you're actually able to
work within and understand all your
different attack vectors in your routes
which really shows how he you know
developed that methodology and why he is
so good at what he does you know and
this is the whole team so it's not just
orange but this is his the um the
research team that he's associated with
yeah and even like in a recent live
hacking event I'm not gonna
name anything but we saw an example of
this exact type of thing where it's more
of attacking like an appliance uh like
or an OS type package than it is like
even a hardware device I because I think
and I might be mistaking you but it
seems like most of this was from
software analysis like they got a
firmware they pulled it apart they
started figuring out like how does this
OS work what types of services are
running where what's the attack surface
all that kind of stuff and we've seen
that even like you know recently in the
last you know month or two where that
same type of thing exists in modern
companies
um including Google obviously
um and I think it's just a really
interesting attack surface I always love
that type of stuff where it's like it's
right there like in your hands and you
just have to figure out like how it
works and like pull it apart and and
once you can figure out how the secret
sauce works then that's usually where
where all the vulnerabilities live but I
also love that in the timeline the first
the first entry of the timeline is a cve
from 2005. oh my gosh which is it's like
a a code like Java code injection yeah
Java code injection and it's the CBE
from 2005 that links to a secless you
know disclosure man back in the wild
west days used to be like a mailing list
it's got like an at metaspleet.com email
hdmr this guy this is this is legit so
cool so cool yeah so that's a it's just
a really cool really cool blog post
I'd recommend you give it a read just to
again this is one of those rare glimpses
into like who I would classify as an
elite hacker oh yeah for sure I'm just
like understanding that mindset and the
thought process and the exploitation
process and the whole start to finish
path of how do you take something as
abstract as like a Google search
Appliance or like a server box or an OS
image and take it all the way to a
vulnerability that you can then report
and get a bounty for oh yeah hopefully
well yeah I'm not yeah in the scenario
yeah maybe hoping to get a bounty but uh
it doesn't look like they Google came
through on that one but um just for
those of you that don't get to go and
read the blog post
um this summary of what ended up
happening here was after like dumping
all of the source code and getting
access to the the um the firmware for
this uh the the vulnerabilities which
are you know being exploited are
actually very simple it's just you've
got a basic LF injection
um you know something's getting it's an
art it's a command injection in a
specific parameter where you just put
you know your your um uh what is it is
it OA yeah it's OA uh percent OA in this
scenario and then add another command
right after it so it's just like a very
standard shell you know injection and
then
um and later on they've just got a very
textbook
um uh lfi or lfd technically
um and so these are also vulnerabilities
that they were able to discover and
explain from a remote perspective rather
than you know
interacting directly with the physical
device
um so from an exploitation scenario you
know from an exploitation perspective
the bugs were not like blow your mind
crazy stuff like you normally see with
orange and his research team but the
approach was really cool to breaking
down an iot device and that was what I
really appreciated about this article
yeah same
all right last one for the um for the
News segment and then we'll jump into
the uh to the content for this episode
um bit Quark finally after four years
after four long years of waiting has
released short scan
um their tool for uh exploding the uh
tilde tilde you know enumeration method
with um Windows short names
um so that's really exciting for those
of you that aren't familiar with that
technique uh for specific IIs servers
actually a lot of IIs servers
Um this can help you enumerate the first
I want to say it's like six characters
of
um any file and folder and then the
first uh you're in the file extension
for that or the first three characters
of the file extension for those files
and folders um and so that's it's really
helpful for when you're doing recon on
IIs environments and this tool utilizes
some new techniques to try to uh get you
the full uh path the full file name not
just the short file name
um which isn't present in a bunch of
other tools that we use for this so I'm
definitely excited to give this one a
poke next time I'm going after IIs uh
targets yeah so I believe this is on any
IIs 8.3 and earlier or maybe it's only
8.3 but
um but yeah something like that no it's
it's a ton of them yeah they're like
almost all of them are vulnerable to it
by default I think yeah yeah so I mean
it's still definitely out there it's
funny because I was just looking back at
the original repo from erzl oh I think
we actually talked about last episode we
did yeah yeah and uh he has like the OG
tool for this is what I would say like I
think I've been using this same tool
since at least probably since the
beginning of when I started using this I
believe shelves was actually the one who
told me about this this vulnerability
even existing
um and if you look at the tool like the
first uh well not the first commit but
there is a commit in the root of it from
ursul that is from nine years ago from
from 2014. oh my gosh and the title of
the repo is I had a short name scanner
20 2012 to 2023 and still giving so it
seems like this has been
uh you know there for a very long time
um it's good to see new tools pop up uh
that can do stuff either faster or
better or in a different way
um you know as much as I love using
tools that are written in Java I think I
would prefer one that's written in going
so uh but that's not to say that the
original is scary yeah yeah yeah exactly
that's that's the nice thing so like the
original tool
um is still you know being actively
maintained there was a commit two days
ago
um and they actually are still actually
linked to Big quarks short scan tool in
the in the is short name scanner repo
the original one so
um I think it's awesome
um you know it's awesome to see you know
people still maintaining this stuff and
making sure it works and adding new
vectors uh to make it quicker and easier
to scan and exploit so I'm not a huge
Recon guy as I've talked about on the
podcast like I don't do a bunch of Recon
but this is one of the techniques that
if you skip this you're really missing
some gold because
um like it like you know if you're just
if you get a really finely tuned list
that's great but if you're actually able
to leak the contents of like arbitrary
names that is like freaking gold huge I
mean there's so much hidden
functionality like just that alone like
hidden functionality web configs like
um path reversals knowing knowing what
files exist like all that kind of stuff
is
you know super super critical like 99 of
the time just on its own and so being
able to have that leverage that you can
then exploit and know a path name or
um maybe be able to access a file that
you shouldn't be able to access or
anything like that
um you know this this type of info is
super super helpful to have and I I
think anytime I see an IIs server um I
typically run it because it's a super
easy win if it works and if it doesn't
work it is very low cost yeah so
actually when I was in the Recon game
like I I actually I'll give this one
away for you that are doing recon stuff
but I would actually have an automation
that was did would detect IIs and then
run this on every IIs server that was
vulnerable and then just take the output
and like look at it for like sort of
sketchy stuff like dot back files right
like
um you know backups or old files and you
know and there's there's a bunch of
other regex that I had and stuff like
that that would kind of trigger weird
stuff but um yeah you can find some
really easy wins with like web
config.back or something like that
um and this this tool can definitely tip
you off to it so keep that in mind and
definitely check out bigquark's new tool
yeah for sure all right should we get it
our
esoteric web vulnerabilities let's do it
man
um let me take a sip of water first
because I've got a bit of a sore throat
and then we'll get into it we're gonna
have to move pretty quickly because we
do not have uh we've got a lot of of
stuff to cover and not a ton of time but
um yeah first up config file injection
so while I drink this water tell the
people about it cool yeah so config
injection file injection pretty much
what you would expect and we talked a
little bit about this during the
hardware episode I think yeah
um but basically this is uh if you're
working with an assistant actually
actually hold on let me let me let me
just stop here really quickly okay so I
I just wanna I just want to highlight
this before we jump right into this okay
so these phones what we're talking about
today like we said like he alluded to
these are esoteric web phones these are
volumes they're at the top of my list
and in Joel's as well in some part
um of volumes that I feel like you
probably don't know about that you
should probably know about because I see
these a lot at live hacking events and I
see these um you know in the wild and
Bug Bounty quite a bit and having these
sort of tools in your belt uh really
really helpful
um so make sure you're paying attention
especially do these first couple ones
because they're they're really really
helpful okay yeah sorry I wanted to want
to give that totally fine Joel go get it
okay yeah yeah no and I'll actually I'll
tee off on that and say that um some of
them are more common than others
um this first one probably not as common
but some of the other ones definitely a
lot more common and definitely a lot
more uh instances of it out there that I
think you could exploit so for config
file injection typically this is going
to be a case where maybe there's a
configuration endpoint a lot of times
this is on iot devices or Hardware
devices or something more local because
that type of stuff doesn't really get uh
you know revealed externally for like a
web service typically it's not going to
be writing to like its DHCP config or
something like that from just like an
API endpoint on you know example.com
right I've seen it I've seen it yeah
yeah it exists that's not to say it's
not there but it's a lot less common and
I personally have seen it significantly
more often in like routers and smart
devices and iot whatevers right like
that's typically where you're going to
see it is in the those type of more like
Niche devices that are much closer to
like an API that's talking directly with
the OS or the system versus an API
that's talking to a service that's
running on an OS within a system
um so config file injections is when you
can write stuff into the config file
um oftentimes this I think in order to
exploit it successfully oftentimes
you're going to need to have an
understanding of what the config file
actually looks like so some type of file
read or file disclosure or access to the
OS or error yeah for both errors
anything like that just to get an
understanding for what the format is and
what stuff looks like around it I think
a lot of these cases typically rely on
like weird types of parsing behavior for
you to be able to exploit it so one
example
is DNS mask where DNS mask if you write
multiple instances of certain directives
within the config file it will
basically ignore the first instance and
only read the second instance but that's
not true for everything some of the
directives can only appear one time and
so understanding is your value being
written multiple times is it being
written one time how long is the line
that it's being written into all those
types of things really matter a lot and
so that's why having some sort of
information over both errors or access
to the file system or something like
that is really really helpful when
you're trying to exploit these
successfully
but they exist I think in a lot more
cases than you might expect and
typically it's really just understanding
what sort of weird functionality is
built in and exists that you can then
exploit to your advantage so DNS mask
for example has this thing called tftp I
did not even know this was a thing until
we exploited it that one time so tftp is
like a weird service it's kind of like
FTP and it runs on what is it Port uh I
think it's Port 69. yeah exactly yeah so
it's like you know super weird
um
yeah you could basically specify like a
file path and it operates kind of like
an FTP server and that you could just
like read files sometimes you can write
files
um there are weird permission checks and
stuff but
if you can inject into you know the
system config file depending on who this
is running as what user this is running
as then you might have full root
arbitrary file read through a completely
separate Port that wasn't even open or
exposed initially but because you've
made changes to the config file it's now
listening on Port 69 and now you can hit
you know the file system and you can
read Etsy password or whatever yeah
um yeah so so like you said you know
it's very it's very dependent on getting
a good grip on where you're at in the
system which is why you see people like
orange and and um and uh that's and no
team whenever they're breaking down a
Target they always always tried their
absolute best to get their hands on
source code because if you can get your
hands on source code you just get such a
better understanding of what's happening
and you can craft these crazy bones that
have these amazing outcomes and this
config file injection piece kind of like
kind of like you said it's a little bit
rare but I feel like it's not that rare
in that
um like a lot of systems that are
interfacing with other services so you
know in the scenario that that we were
just talking about with DNS mask you
know maybe you're spinning up a DNS
server right
and uh and you know you want to have DNS
Mass active and so you're dynamically
generating that DNS Mass configuration
file and that's where the injection
happens because you need to uh you know
spin up that DNS Mass server with um
user input as the configuration file and
so
um you know situations like that
whenever you're interacting with other
services there's a there's a high risk
for this you know oftentimes you're
injecting it via a template
um and you know the templating doesn't
necessarily have the right control
characters to prevent you from escaping
the block that you're in in the code and
we can use comments and stuff like that
to clean up after us so
um oftentimes it's pretty easy to inject
into that configuration file your own
malicious input
um and that can result in some crazy
vulnerabilities but it's also going to
result in some crazy exploitation
scenarios
where you are reading the documentation
more than you ever thought you would be
reading the documentation
um and getting very very familiar
getting very intimate with this uh with
this application with the configuration
that you're injecting into and that just
makes for some crazy interesting and fun
bugs yeah and uh it's so much more
satisfying what it pops too because it's
like it's like you've gone through a
whole journey just to get to that point
and then finally everything works and
your payload works and you pop it and it
you know it calls back or whatever and
it's awesome it's an awesome feeling
somebody asked me the other day what is
what my favorite moment hacking was and
I had to put some thought into it and it
but it was I think it was one of the
bugs I collaborated on with you when
finally we shelled this this iot device
I was just like oh my gosh I love this
so much so yeah it was like a super
culmination of of so much time and
effort and yeah the payoff is super
worth it yeah for sure so let me see if
there's anything else
um here that we wanted to talk about
um yeah so we I guess I'll well you
mentioned DNS mask we've also seen this
in dhcpd uh nginx and Apache um
configurations uh injections so
definitely be on the lookout for
anything that's sort of interacting with
these services and keep um file or
config file injection in your mind next
time you're doing your next assessment
yeah yeah exactly like if you see a
dhcpd server it doesn't mean that you
need a zero day in DHCP or dhcpd like it
doesn't mean like oh they're running the
latest version so it's not exploitable
move on to the next thing there's no cve
or whatever it's totally up to
configuration and how this stuff is
working because it can be a perfectly
regularly validly configured instance
but they're doing something wacky
somewhere else within the system and you
can exploit that behavior to natively
get a shell or escalate your privileges
within the system and that that's like
the real powerful thing is this isn't
like a zero day or anything this is just
how you can configure it legitimately to
do weird stuff that we can take
advantage of as an attacker yeah great
summary
um next one that I had on the list was
client-side path traversal
now this one's a little bit weird
because you think of path traversal
normally as a you know server-side sort
of thing you're you're putting something
in either a query parameter or a path
um and you're directly in your URL and
you're getting to access to some path
that you that you didn't previously have
access to by using some iteration of dot
dot slash or combination of dot dot
slashes right
um client-side path traversal occurs
when you are able to inject via a query
parameter or a hash or something in the
user's browser so you know the users
click the link or you've redirected the
user to a specific spot
um and that page is uh loading a
resource based off of your attacker
based input so let's say for example you
redirect them to google.com example one
two three four and they try to load a
CSS page that that's like slash ESS
slash one two three four dot CSS right
so your one two three four from the path
is being taken and put into a resource
that's being did then you know if it's
URL decoding it and stuff like that
you can try to use some path traversal
sequences to hit a different part of the
application hopefully get a redirect and
get yourself a full CSS injection on
that page which as as we all know from
listening to other episodes of critical
thinking can result in some very
critical stuff
um so uh that's sort of what I had on
client-side path traversal you got any
other thoughts on that Joel yeah I mean
this isn't a client-side past reversal
but I think one of the things that's
kind of closely related to this that I
really like as a class of bug and this
is kind of it's not really talked about
a ton but I think it's like packed
reversal through ID and oftentimes I see
this with like there's a post request
that includes an ID in it for example
there's say it's posting a Json body one
of the parameters is ID in the body and
it's a uuid or something well oftentimes
you can put uuid slash dot dot slash
some other arbitrary path some arbitrary
internal path or something and that just
gets fully concatenated into an internal
request and it's it's like in the line
of ssrf kind of srf Slash path reversal
yeah but it's a really really
interesting technique and I see it
exploited all the time like all over the
place is something that I now regularly
check for whenever I see an ID being
sent is let me just try putting a dot
dot slash and then like the same ID
after it and just see if that still
works because that's often a really good
indicator of whether or not it's working
and that's kind of
um I don't know it's a it's not quite
esoteric it's a little more common but
it's like a weird
um route for exporting like srfs and
kind of a server-side patch reversal if
you want to call it that
um and I think it it deserves to be
mentioned alongside this yeah for sure
man I I've seen those all the time and
excuse me they're very impactful bugs if
you can get them to work especially if
you understand
what API is being hit in the back end or
you have some introspection to that
through the error or something like that
those are some crazy crazy bugs so and
then just to clarify the reason why
you're saying put so let's say we've got
ID or uuid equals you know one two three
four dash whatever then you put a slash
at the end you put a dot dot slash right
so that would delete the ID you just
split in right yep and then you put the
same ID again so that that path is
should be normalizing to the same thing
it was without having
the any of the path traversals in there
right right and you can imagine this in
in the back end scenarios basically like
one service is hitting another service
the way it does that is yeah yeah
microservices hitting it through an HTTP
request and it goes you know other
internal service dot host slash ID or
whatever slash API slash get slash ID or
something right however you want to
imagine how it's being put in there and
then if you're giving it a full value
and it's not being sanitized and that's
just being chucked onto the end of that
URL your past reversal is going to
affect that internal microservice call
and be able to hit other API endpoints
and other things within that other
service that you may not have been
intended to to hit and I I see so much
impact approved from these all the time
it's really insane some of the biggest
uh baddest vulnerabilities I've ever
seen are caused by this and it's
something that seems so simple and
straightforward so if you're not
checking for that be sure to check for
that because it's it's again it's it's
not quite an easy win but it's it's it
definitely gives you a lot of Leverage
yeah and I think it's systemic on the
targets as well normally because the
target is using a microservices based
architecture so if you find one you're
likely to find lots of other unique
issues as well with their own unique
fixes
um and so I'll actually also Link in the
in the notes for this episode
um that uh there's a blog post by Sam
Curry and I uh that did let's see when
did we I'm not sure this is a long time
ago that we had done this
um yeah I mean Sam is like the king of
this type of film he's the one who I
like learned it off of and I see so many
crazy impactful bugs that are that are
shown by him using this uh I I wasn't
sure which ones I I should even talk
about because I know like some of them
are not public so yeah Starbucks you
have a good example
it's public there's a blog post so we'll
link it in the description if you
haven't seen it that's great but
um Joel so you we we got off topic there
the one that I'm trying to talk about
here is the client-side path traversal
which is different very notedly
different so it's very notably different
yes um this is something that happens in
the user's browser I mentioned yeah this
happens in style sheets but it also
happens in JS files and it can also
happen just in in fetch in age asks
requests right so requests that are
being sent by the page via JavaScript
and those are very impactful as well
because if you can Traverse in a context
where it's trying to like let's say it's
sending a post request to like you know
load your news feed or whatever right if
you can control that path and you can
hit you know make it hit like slash
delete account and that delete account
doesn't require any you know parameters
then you can force user to just delete
their account I found this bug before
um and so definitely be on the lookout
there's a lot of different implications
it can result in CSS injection it can
result in xss it can result in um this
sort of sea surf sort of outcome
um and then the other thing that I I
don't know how much of an issue this
still is but um there used to be this
thing called 401 injection where you can
inject a uh you know a prompt where it
would pop up and it would ask the user
to type in their credentials right and
then that prompt was actually coming
from your website but it was on the page
that uh you know you injected into
um that used to be a bug I don't I I
didn't get the chance to check it before
this episode to see whether it's still
active or not but um if that could also
be a potential outcome from this sort of
uh client-side path traversal if you can
find an open redirect and redirect to
your own site where you serve a 401.
yeah I do wonder if that's still a thing
I remember that that class of
vulnerability but I don't actually know
know if it's still accessible that's
that's with like uh realm like
authentication stuff right yeah yeah and
I'm I'm pretty confident it's it's
possible in at least one of the major
browsers I just can't remember which one
it is so we'll have to check that out
I've got some good guesses and it's
probably not Crow yeah it's definitely
not Chrome
cool all right next one cookie bombing
have you ever heard of have you heard of
cookie bombing slash do you do cookie
bombing Joel before I get put on a list
here uh
uh yeah so I I hadn't real I the I'd
heard of the name and I understand like
the concept but until I actually read
through file the scriptures
um slides about this specifically now it
definitely clicks
and I would kind of tie it in with the
next one that we were going to talk
about which is cookie jar overflow but
basically these two classes are
um exploiting just like sort of native
browser Behavior around how cookies are
set and sent and so oftentimes there
have been new security features that
have been added to like how cookies work
for example hdp only
um or site secure or whatever
um and that make it so that they're only
accessible within certain contexts and
they're only sent within certain
contexts and you know if it's HTTP only
then your JavaScript can't read and
write it but that's fine because
sometimes you control a web server that
is doing that over HTTP instead of doing
that over JavaScript and so
with cookie bombing for example you can
set multiple cookies for the same host
on different paths and when they get
sent the browser doesn't distinguish
whether or not you know oftentimes well
maybe it does well I mean I mean it's
supposed to do pads the paths piece um
you can use the different paths to bomb
specific endpoints so like you said you
know the the this is abusing a sort of
browser level problem with cookie
management which is if you send too many
cookies uh the browser will still send
them to the to the server but the server
will sort of I guess this is sort of a
server-side issue then the server is
going to freak out and be like okay whoa
whoa this request is way too big please
please stop right and it's gonna I
forget what status code it sends it's
it's some 400 status code
um but it freaks out and it doesn't like
that right
um and so you can set you know you can
set enough cookies that the browser will
happily send along which essentially
doses your access to a specific website
until you delete your cookies right
um and you literally do that just by
saying all right cookie one equals 9999
A's cookie two equals 999 A's you know
and then like do that until you've blown
up the whole request right and um and
that will result in the whatever user's
browser you're you're setting this in
and not being able to access the Target
the Target website until they clear
their cookies
um and this can be particularly tricky
here's here's a here's a fun one here if
you do this on a sub part of a website
that is not the top URL because what
people will do sometimes is they can't
access the website they'll delete the
cookies for the specific website that
they're on right which is their top URL
but let's say use for example you Cookie
bombed the API dot domain right the
api.domain.com that's never in the
user's top level browser so if they try
to delete their cookies for that website
then they can't do it right without
without going in there and actually
deleting all of their cookies which is
kind of a pain in the ass because it it
logs you out of literally every single
website yeah um so this is this is a
really cool Vault and you can do this
with just a gadget that sets allows you
to inject a cookie on the website which
is fairly common
um and this is also a great way for you
to
um show an effect to availability which
UPS your CVSs score and it really helps
with like stuff like subdomain takeovers
to show impact
yeah yeah there's actually a cool tool
idea I just thought of right now as you
were saying that which would be
something that basically you could plug
in your existing cbss score or maybe
like say you have a bug and it meets
certain criteria within CVSs and then
the tool would tell you if you could get
that if you could change this one factor
it would take your bug from a medium to
a high or even two crate or something
that's a great idea so so you'd have you
could put in your CVSs score and then
it'll tell you okay your easiest
escalations are going to be all right if
you can figure out how to affect
availability just a little bit you know
maybe try cookie bombing or something
like that dude that's a great idea
someone's got to build that yeah yeah uh
not us though yeah I got too much going
on yeah critical thinking Community
please please take that and run away
somebody make that to us even if it
takes four years big work yeah at pick
work uh no that's great um and the the
other thing that I was gonna say um
specifically on app cache Urban um on
cookie bombing is you can use it with
stuff as well like like app cache
um because what will happen if you
define an app cache on a specific page
if there's an error that occurs at the
browser level uh it it will sub in a
different content so it's perfect for
cookie bombing and I've seen this I've
seen Franz abuse this I've seen file
descriptor abuse this and he actually
mentions it in his talk entitled The
Cookie Monster in your browsers which I
think was the talk you were mentioning
earlier
um and he also mentions how you can use
it to get it to not consume oauth tokens
because you can keep on the specific
oauth endpoint right yeah
such an interesting attack Vector so
yeah I guess if you basically cookie
bomb and it sets too many cookies the
request will fail yeah the requests
the outbound request will still contain
like the credentials or whatever in the
URL and so you can because it's like a
failed request it doesn't hit like
iframe options
I guess is that correct well so there's
some there's some intricacies like that
but the one the one that's really you
know how helpful in this scenario is
like and it can help you avoid iframe
options and some CSP stuff as well but
in this scenario you you're when as soon
as that that code lands on the page
where the Callback is it gets used and
consumed right so even if you have a
reference to that window and with an XS
or something you like you can't consume
you can't get to that token in time
because it's gonna you're gonna lose the
race every time and it's going to
consume the left token and you can't get
an account takeover but if you Cookie
bomb the end point where that oauth code
is getting returned to when it goes to
that page it's going to fail but you
could because you're the same origin you
can still reach into that page grab the
you know
um window location.href and pull the
code out of there which would allow you
to get escalate your xss to ATO it's
just such a such a great technique I
love it yeah that's awesome yeah yeah
um on cook so then like tangential yeah
the cookie jar overflow which is kind of
similar in like sending too many cookies
or like yeah sort of overflowing how the
browser is behaving but you actually
have a whole tool for this which I did
not know about called check cookie jar
overflow yeah I don't know what what do
you call it but it's a layout on your
it's on your domain yeah it's a link
apps.dev you guys can check it out this
is just kind of it's just kind of like
if you click on it it's kind of like
just a scrappy little website with like
a freaking
um Apache you know yeah it's literally
20 20 lines of HTML including the script
and essentially um what it allows so I
actually before prepping for this
episode I was like all right let me you
know I always prefer this episode I'm
like you know all right I'm gonna drop
some knowledge I'm gonna you know show
them all these cool like weird esoteric
levels and then I get in there and I and
I was researching for cookie bombing and
I find this cookie jar overflow thing
and I'm like what the heck is that I've
never even heard of that and so I found
it and I think it was on the site hacker
yeah hack tricks that tricks which is
really cool like that's a great website
by the way
um yeah did we talk about this last
episode too we might have but what
happened yeah yeah but again this is
like one of those like informational
type documentation websites that we
talked about where this type of resource
is something that like keep it in your
bookmarks and just like if you're ever
stuck on something check all of the ones
that you have bookmarked because
oftentimes there'll be some like weird
Edge stuff or just some like really
interesting techniques that somebody has
documented somewhere that you can take
advantage of to escalate your
vulnerability at the next level yeah
there's so many awesome like just weird
things in this hat tricks that XYZ um
website so I'll do my best to sort of go
in and digest some of that and and put
it at back into the podcast
um in an auditory format but when I was
prepping for the the it was for the
cookie bombing I ran across this cookie
jar overflow which is really cool and I
actually usually
um had I known about this
um at the last live hacking event I
would have been able to save a friend a
lot of time because he had to go uh down
this this path to get rid of this cookie
that he needed to be gone
um and uh he could have just used this
technique
um and it would have just he would have
been able to get it gone in just a
second so the technique just to be clear
is um you essentially just set a bunch
of cookies in the browser for a specific
domain and each domain has a limit on
how many cookies can be associated with
it in the browser that's the cookie jar
and the cookie jar limit
um and so if you if you exceed that
limit cookies start getting deleted
oldest first so you can Edge out the
other cookies in the user's browser even
if you don't know the name of that
cookie so let's say for example you have
a cookie
um you know session uh off session XYZ
random string equals whatever their
session token is right you don't know
what that random string is so you can't
overwrite that cookie and if it's an
HTTP only cookie you can't access it
from the JavaScript side even if you can
set cookies right so you need that
cookie gone so you can do a session
fixation
um and how are you going to get rid of
it because you don't know the name of it
right so um this is a cool technique you
can use to do that by setting a bunch of
cookies overflowing the cookie jar and
then being able to use your own values
um and one of the things I thought was
really interesting is you can Edge out
HTTP only cookies even from a non-hdp
only context which I think is really
cool and seems like a little bit of an
issue right
yeah well I mean and again this is like
weird Behavior that's kind of intended
but also not intended like yeah you know
it it abuses like one two
functionalities that both need to exist
at the same time and they kind of
collide with each other potentially
right where it's like HTTP only
shouldn't be able to be set by
JavaScript but if you set a bunch of
other cookies with JavaScript eventually
you'll have too many cookies and the
HTTP only cookies will just get removed
and like yeah you know that what the
browsers could just have infinite memory
no like you can right so like these two
things have to both exist and there's no
real easy compromise there so it's super
super interesting behavior and one of
those things that you know have it
documented keep it in the back of your
brain and then when you need it you'll
have it yeah for sure so we'll add some
links down below the little
um sort of tool that I that you
mentioned before that you saw in the
dock that was just something that I sort
of scraped together to help people
understand to wear their cookie jar
overflow limit is in the browser so you
guys can check it out we'll link it down
below it's apps.reinerator.dev cookie or
slash check cookie jar overflow.html in
camel case of course you know probably
easier to just click the link just click
the link in the description yeah
um but essentially if you go to that and
you click on it it will set a bunch of
cookies and tell you where your cookie
jar limit is in your browser
um I ran it in Chrome and prep for this
episode and it puts it at 180 cookies
um the range for this is between I think
150 to 180 but every time I've run it
I've gotten 180 so
um you know you should be able to do it
pretty easily yeah and maybe as some off
off the Pod research I would be curious
if this matters more uh like the length
of the cookie if that matters at all or
if it's just
purely number of cookies do you know I
think it's just pure number of cookies
because I was just setting let me take a
look at the code really quickly here you
say off the Pod research and then you
know we're gonna do it right away yeah
we're gonna look right now yeah no it's
just it's just you know check and then
the index equals the index so I'm just
saying check one equals one check two
equals two and that sort of thing and
it's overflowing at 180. so I I think I
think it's just a number of cookies
thing cool cool yeah awesome all right
next one dude um this one is cross site
leak
um yeah sort of similar to Sea surf
um it's a little bit less common
um and I think it is going to be a uh I
think it will be an increasingly
um common vulnerability over the next
couple years
um I've seen a couple people exploit
this uh successfully at live hacking
events and I've seen it result in a
critical once
um and essentially the concept of it is
well it's sort of like a sea surf right
in that you're forcing the user to have
uh have their browser make a request but
instead of having an action performed on
behalf of the user using some sort of
side Channel whether it be the number of
frames on the resulting page or an error
you know a 200 or a 404 you can
determine whether or not
the user is uh in some sort of some
State
um and so you can determine you know
something about the user's presence in
the application uh based off of that
um and so I there's a couple techniques
that you can use for this year
um one of the ones that I think is
really cool is frame counting so
essentially you can open up a a new tab
in a window and one of the few things
that you can access cross
um cross uh origin right when you're
reaching into a different frame
um is the frames length attribute on a
window so you can see how many Sub sub
frames are in the application so let's
say you submit a a search into some sort
of cross-site search functionality where
you've got a query parameter you know
equals whatever and if there are results
then there will be another iframe on the
page maybe it'll show you like a preview
of the results or something like that if
there aren't results then there won't be
an iframe and you can use that
difference along with the frame length
trick to determine whether or not that
user has access to whatever thing you're
searching for in the browser which can
result in a in a pretty interesting leak
of information I think
yeah yeah it's super interesting I had
never heard of this technique at all um
there's a whole domain for it xsleaks
dot Dev
um and it basically just goes over like
a lot of the different like browser
features and tricks and nuances and
defense mechanisms for the other side as
well
um and yeah this is a really useful
resource I'm gonna definitely put this
in my bookmarks
um and I was just really you know it's
cool to see this type of again this type
of more like informational research
that's documenting like Strange
Behaviors things that exist things that
you might be able to use to chain with
your existing vulnerabilities to make
them more impactful
um yeah it's really interesting I think
a lot of companies care about leakage of
data even if it's an oracle type thing
like this is yeah and it's definitely a
useful I've had some companies say no to
that before you know I've had like some
Oracle related stuff like it you know is
this user an admin or is this user you
know a member of a specific organization
or something like that
um I think those I think those could
definitely be helpful in attack chains
but you definitely got to realize when
you're submitting these sort of bugs
that
um it is sort of a risk you know
um so definitely keep that in mind
um one of the things that I did think of
well first let me let me talk about some
of the ways you can exploit this so we
talked about frame counting right that's
that technique where you can
um determine the number of sub excuse me
subframes
on a window object there's also another
one that this is really cool uh Joel I
thought you'd appreciate this one
because I've never seen this one before
um you can actually count the
history.length
um and it can release information so
what happens is you're on an attacker's
page user clicks a button you open up a
new tab right the user is in that new
tab you're distracting the user in the
previous tab
um you can iterate through
um some you can go to some URL and if
that URL redirects it will take you to a
a third URL right and then you can
redirect back to using the window object
you can redirect back to the the main
page so now you're on the same origin
between the two pages and you check the
history.length and it will tell you how
many you know changes in the history
have occurred since you know you you
check the history.length
um and so that's another way that you
can sort of leak really cool
um sort of side Channel stuff and I'm
not sure how like how this could be used
um this could definitely be used in a
way to tell if a user is a part of an
organization or not that's definitely
something that's possible
um uh but yeah I'm really interested to
hear you know what other stuff people
comes up with using this technique
because I think I think there are
definitely possibilities for right yeah
yeah I think as browsers get more
hardened we're gonna have to get a
little more creative with these types of
techniques that we're talking about
because some of the things that we took
for granted as what ways to easily
escalate bugs like before HTTP only just
being able to read all the cookies from
JavaScript right like that's not a thing
anymore so now you have to figure out
more creative ways to get information
about the user or infer different states
and and all that kind of stuff so yeah
it's really awesome to see this type of
research and even in the era of same
site cookies as well you know we've had
that restriction come in place now
um yeah there's we're even having to get
more more creative using window.open
rather than using iframes and such so
we're losing some of this flexibility
but
um the last one that I think is really
interesting sort of a cross-site leak
technique that I found out was if you
open up a PDF in Chrome okay
it will provide you with a post message
based interface
for that PDF even cross-origin so I was
thinking this would be a really cool
technique um an attack Factor okay let's
say you've got an application that has a
customer
um you know you can in Click you know go
to a specific URL and it will load up a
PDF for that specific customer right and
that's a numeric ID so you know once
again you do the window.opentrick and
then you start iterating through
customer IDs right if and you can tell
whether it's a PDF or not via these post
message interaction so now you're
iterating through iterating through
iterating through and you can tell how
many customers a given person has by
whether the response is a PDF or not via
this crosite link and I think that's
definitely some impactful stuff
um for sure you know being able to tell
whether or not you know their customer
how at what pace their customer base is
increasing
um yeah so that's another cool technique
there that I didn't know about the the
PDF thing exposing a post message
listener that's kind of crazy yeah yeah
that that competitive intelligence stuff
is is pretty value valuable to a lot of
companies yeah
cool
all right so sorry for renting on that
one no no that's totally fine I love
cross site leaks I think that's such a
cool type of honorability I don't even
know where you found this domain it's
it's really cool yeah all right so the
next one UNC path leaks you want to take
that or should I
oh yeah I can talk a little bit about it
but um so UNC was what is it Universal
Network convention naming convention
um basically it's like the paths that
you see on uh typically on Windows where
it's like backslash backslash something
um and so oftentimes you can inject into
these in like a ton of different places
um it'll be maybe in like a file
inclusion or maybe it'll be a path
traversal or a desktop application yeah
a desktop application or something like
that that has that's running again
typically on Windows
um but it's a really good way to
escalate and sort of pivot and navigate
horizontally within a system that maybe
you can escalate that vertically but
oftentimes it's going to be pivoting to
other services or systems or network
drives or something like that that are
accessible within the host that you can
then take to your advantage to really
prove the impact of your of your bug and
just showing that you can interact with
stuff outside of that application or
within other parts of the network is
already like a really big impact
provider so
um you know yeah very very along the
same lines as like patch reversal path
injection that type of stuff but yeah
was there specific things you wanted to
mention yeah well the other thing that I
wanted to mention is like the use of
repeater with this so let's say for
example you have a um a deep link you
can provide to a Windows desktop app and
that will open up you know some file of
your choice right you can provide it
with a UNC path there
um which is a path to link to us to a
specific server and a share you on that
server right
so it'll happen by default is Windows
we'll try to authenticate into that
share and it will send your ntlm V2 hash
to that server even though it's not in
your local network
it doesn't happen you know it could be
anywhere and you can use a tool called
excuse me a tool called repeater to
catch that and pull the hash that'll
leak a couple things to you one it'll
leak the username of the
um server or whoever's uh you know using
that specific whoever's making that
connection so if on the desktop app it
would be you know the user of the of the
PC on an actual server when you've got
like an srf sort of thing that would be
the the server username and then also
the ntlm V2 hash of that user which one
it is a password hash um that you can
crack offline so that could definitely
be helpful for proving impact
and I believe there are some cool things
you can do with ntlm V2 hashes as well
that's beyond just password cracking but
I have to research into that but I know
for sure that you can then take that
password and crack it offline which is
um a pretty helpful way to increase your
ability to Pivot within that Network
yeah totally this is one of those things
that's a little bit outside of my realm
of like familiar knowledge it's
important stuff yeah exactly it's more
like uh you know you're doing like a
network pen test and you know you found
some vulnerable windows image or
instance or something like that
um more kind of on the like the
Metasploit type route not that that's
like a bad thing but like more like
there are there's lots of tools and
stuff that are built around this type of
stuff and typically the type of hacking
that we're doing is like web hacking or
like yeah mobile hacking maybe Hardware
hacking but generally not like internal
pen test type stuff where the ntlm
hashes are going to be leaked
um but I think there's a huge body
resource uh resources and research out
there that covers this type of
information and how to exploit ntlm
hashes and what to do with them I know
Mimi cats is a pretty popular tool
um for that type of stuff so yeah the
the
um so I think it's it's very important
to have this sort of cross-discipline
um yeah knowledge though because you
know we've seen especially in the
desktop app exploitation Arena which is
something we see in bug Bounty a decent
bit still
um I've seen this bug you know results
this little Quirk result in uh much
higher bounties for some of the desktop
level applications
um yeah because you know understandably
uh software providers don't want to be
responsible for leaking their users ntlm
V2 hash to whoever
um so keep that in mind if you're doing
any desktop level hacking whether it be
you know electron based stuff or native
clients or whatever
yeah because again like this is like a
pivot from application vulnerability to
OS problem right where like if your
application is leaking a hash to the OS
user you've now compromised that whole
user within the entire OS it's no longer
about your application it's about the
entire user and if their system is
exposed at all now you can use those
credentials to gain access to their
system even further and like totally
exploit the user beyond the application
and the implications of just that
application so I think for sure it's a
huge impact provider if you can figure
out a way to exploit it effectively yeah
absolutely okay
um let's let's have this next one be the
last one here
um I entitled this one impactful link
hijack
um because we've seen some link
hijacking vulnerabilities and stuff like
that pop up on the hactivity you know in
the past that are kind of crappy that
are just like yeah you know you're
you're took over your Instagram on your
home page yeah somebody forgot to you
know refresh this domain or whatever and
that that's kind of like okay you know I
feel like that's more of a QA issue or
like a web design team issue you know
it's less of a issue but there is a
specific
um
subset of these issues call that I I
just deem impactful link hijacking
um which um when is when this sort of
thing happens in the CI flow or within
within source code
excuse me
man this cold is really getting the
better of me yeah it's funny because
over the last like 55 minutes or so
you've progressively gotten more and
more like someone who smokes six packs
of cigarettes a day yeah
yeah that's the struggle with having a
podcast is like oh man I gotta get out
here and talk every single week with my
voice
um finally all those meetings are are
putting me to good use yeah exactly so
so yeah just the thing that I wanted
people to take away with this one thing
is like if you can go to a GitHub repo
and like find a script that's being
curled or or
um find a a old domain that's being
reached out to or like an S3 bucket S3
buckets are really common Heroku
instances that sort of thing and you're
able to inject yourself either in the CI
pipeline or in the source code
um uh you know context then there can be
some really impactful vulnerabilities
there um yeah I am not doing as much
GitHub scanning anymore I used to be
pretty big on the GitHub scanning
because uh but since they sort of
started cracking down on that sort of
thing I I've I you know various Secrets
being linked and that sort of thing I've
I've spent less time there but I know
for a fact that people are still finding
very impactful vulnerabilities via you
know finding um expired domains or S3
buckets or Hoke instances or whatever
inside of source code and CI pipelines
yep yep and in addition to that um it
doesn't have to be within like a script
automatically if you want to provide an
impact so like
oh I was hacking with a couple weeks ago
um he found a really interesting bug
that was basically exactly this where
there was a set of instructions that
were in a GitHub repo for how to set up
a tool and those instructions included a
bunch of setup commands and in those set
of commands it was pulling down a
resource from an S3 bucket
and that S3 bucket didn't exist and he
was able to take over the S3 bucket and
prove impact by saying look this is in
the readme if somebody were to copy
paste this which is completely a
plausible scenario they would be pulling
resources down from my bucket and you
know it was accepted so I think like
that's just like a great example of like
one it doesn't have to be directly in a
script but like just the fact that
they're using it and they're advocating
for you like the user to be pulling
something from that resource if that
resource doesn't exist anymore that's
direct impact because they're they're
explicitly telling you hey use this
domain well that domain is no longer
safe so I think like anything like down
that
sort of path is a is a good way to to
have impactful link hijacking right it
doesn't always have to be like oh I took
over your Instagram username or whatever
like I think that stuff exists as well
for uh open source code and open source
scripts and all that kind of stuff that
you that you mentioned yeah for sure man
all right I think that's that's a wrap
that's seven
um you know esoteric web vulnerability
types hopefully y'all learned something
from that I I definitely did while
researching for it
um if you guys wouldn't mind definitely
head over to ctbb.show drop your email
in the newsletter subscription there
that would be a big help to us and uh
yeah anything else you got Joel before
we sign off no I think that's it I'm
I've got a bunch of new bookmarks and
tools to download yeah so same same man
I'm gonna go play around with that big
Clark short scan tool right after this
yeah awesome all right hopefully your
your voice and your your cold goes away
and uh hopefully you feel a little
better but I'll see you next week thanks
man yeah hopefully I'll be recovered for
next all right cool peace peace